Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
- Material Arranged and Described in 1997
  - Biographical Material
    - Ada P. McCormick Biography Research Material, (20 boxes); HUG 4255.80
      - Interviews
        - Louise Cabot Wolfe (Hugh Cabot, Jr.'s ex-wife) (Box Box 20)
        - Dr. Alfred Worcester (Box Box 20)
        - Lucy Wright (Box Box 20)
  - Correspondence
    Contains chiefly personal correspondence with family and friends and also several folders of professional correspondence.
    - Correspondence with family and friends, 1870-1939., (15 boxes); HUG 4255.10
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      This collection of correspondence was given to the H. U. Archives by the Ada Peirce McCormick Estate in 1975. Accession numbers: 7664, 7835.
      Custodial History
      Mrs. McCormick had been given these papers in 1935 by Richard Cabot for the purpose of writing a biography of Ella Lyman Cabot. The book was never written and this correspondence, along with Mrs. McCormick's research for the book came to Harvard after her death.
      Includes both Richard and Ella Cabot's letters.
      Correspondents:
      Abbott, Lyman
      Abren, Rosalia
      Adams, Louis
      Addams, Jane
      Alford, Edward B.
      Alleman, L.
      Almy, Helen Cabot
      Almy, Nellie
      Amory, Louise, Anna Harriet
      Andrews, Elisabeth
      Baker, Leslie Talbot
      Baker, Mary O.
      Baker, Sherman Christina
      Balacheff, M.
      Baldwin Family
      Bangs, Mary R.
      Bardwell, Francis
      Barnes, Lilace Reid
      Barringer, Theodore B., Jr.
      Bartlett, Alice M.
      Bassor, N. J.
      Best, Dorothy (see Lovitch, Dorothy Best)
      Best, Sally Creighton
      Blake, Barton
      Bleinie, F. A.
      Block, Celia
      Borden, Fanny
      Bothmer, (von), Gisele
      Bowditch, Vincent Y.
      Bradford, G. G.
      Bradley, Florence
      Bradley, Frances (Dr.) R. M.
      Bradley, Margaret
      Breed, Mary I.
      Brickhead, K.
      Bridge, John L.
      Bridgman, Olive W.
      Bros, Hardy
      Broughton, Helen
      Brown, Cabot
      Brown, Hillyer Emily
      Brown, Jane M.
      Brown, Philip K. Helen (San Francisco)
      Brown, Phoebe
      Brown, W. R.
      Bryant, Viola
      Bullard, Louise
      Bullard, May L.
      Burgess, Augusta
      Burgess, Gelette (Poem - 1896)
      Burleigh, Edith
      Burell, Caroline C.
      Cabot, Anne
      Cabot, Charlotte
      Cabot, Charles M. Bessie
      Cabot, Eliot
      Cabot, Elise
      Cabot, Elizabeth Dwight (RCC's mother)
      Cabot, Ethel (Mrs. F. Elliot Cabot)
      Cabot, Faith (see Pigors, Faith Cabot)
      Cabot, Frederick P.
      Cabot, Henry B.
      Cabot, J. Elliot (RCC's father)
      Cabot, Lucy (see Ames, Lucy Cabot)
      Cabot, Mary C.
      Cabot, R. M.
      Cabot, Sidney
      Cabot, Sylvia (see Walker, Sylvia Cabot)
      Cabot, T. Handasyd
      Cabot, Theodora
      Cabot, Walker
      Calkins, Mary Whiton
      Campbell, Annie
      Campbell, Helen
      Cannon, Ida M.
      Carr, Adelaide K.
      Carson, Luella C.
      Cerf, Katharine (Mrs. Marcel Cerf)
      Chamberlin, Sarah E.
      Campagne, Bertha E. E.
      Chao, Yueh L.
      Chapin, E. Nettie
      Chapin, Erving F.
      Chapin, Mabel H.
      Chapman, Julia (Mrs. William C. Chapman)
      Chapman, Minna
      Chase, Ethel Wolcott
      Chase, J. Frank
      Cheever, Helen
      Cheney, Mary L.
      Chesley, Annie L.
      Clark, Susan Day
      Clark, Walter L.
      Clarke, Alice de V.
      Clarke, Richard
      Clement, Margaret (Mrs. Norman Clement)
      Cleveland, "Lilly"
      Codman, Susan
      Coe, Fanny E.
      Coes, Mary
      Coit, Dorothy
      Colby, Henry
      Colon, Mrs. George E.
      Comstock, Ada (President Radcliffe College)
      Conant, Levi Leonard
      Coolidge, Amy L. (Mrs. Algernon Coolidge)
      Coolidge, Ellen Bayles
      Coolidge, J. Randolph
      Coolidge, Mary S.
      Coolidge, Mea (engaged to RCC very short time)
      Coolidge, M. H. (Mrs. J. Randloph Coolidge)
      Cope, Elizabeth Middleton
      Cornish, Frances
      Cox, George Clarke
      Crandon, Laura
      Crawford, Winifred
      Creighton, Sally R.
      Crile, George
      Crofoot, Mary N.
      Crosby, Margaret
      Crothers, Margery L.
      Cummings, Lydia Lyman
      Cummins, Anne E.
      Cunningham, Francis C.
      Cunningham, Hester
      Curtis, F. G. (Frances G.)
      Daly, Louise Haskell
      Daly, Reginald
      Darling, Grace
      Darling, Harriet
      Darling, Katharine
      Darr, Vera Campbell
      Darwin, Maud
      Davidson, Thomas
      Davis, Pauline Allen Hallowell
      Davison, Marian L.
      Day, Elizabeth R.
      DeBruyn, Mary B.
      DeLacour, Esther Lyman
      Dern, John Sebastian
      Derr, Norman
      Deuprey, Claire
      DeVaber, Beatrice
      Devlin, Marjory Standish
      Dewey, Elizabeth Phelps
      Dewey, Frances (see Rousmaniere, Frances)
      Doe, Ruth C. (Mrs. Charles C. Doe)
      Dorman, Elizabeth J.
      Dow, Margaret Elder
      Draper, Queena (Mrs. B. H. Bristow Draper)
      Drinker, Henry S., Jr.
      Drinker, Sophie
      Dunn, Julia
      Dupriez, M.
      Duveneck, Francis B. Josephine
      Dwight, Edmund
      Dysart, Margaret A.
      Eastman, Winifred
      Eaton, Bertha L.
      Edsall, David L.
      Edwards, Amy B.
      Elder, Margaret (see Dow, Margaret Elder)
      Elder, Sam Ruthanne
      Eliot, Charles W.
      Eliot, Samuel A.
      Ellsworth, Elizabeth
      Emerson, Edward W.
      Emerson, Ellen T.
      Ernst, Helen Amory
      Essenberg, Christine A.
      Evans, Elizabeth Glendower
      Evans, Lydia
      Evarts, Sarah P.
      Fairchild, Sally
      Farmer, Gertrude
      Field, Carrie Leonora
      Field, L.
      Field, Parker B.
      Fileni, Lily
      Filkens, C. W. L.
      Finney, J. M. T. (Dr.)
      Fiske, Annie W.
      Fitz, Henrietta G.
      Flagg, Mary D.
      Flanagan, Thomas E.
      Flint, George M.
      Follett, Mary P.
      Foote, Frances E.
      Forbes, Edith Emerson
      Forbes, W. Cameron
      Forbes, Waldo Emerson
      Fraser, Catharine
      Frazier, Thurlow H.
      Fuller, Lucia F.
      Fuller, Lucy
      Fuller, Mary B.
      Fuster, L.
      Galbraith, Beatrice
      Gannett, W. C.
      Garrett, Alfred C.
      Garrett, Alice Palmer
      Garrett, Francine
      Gates, Donald C.
      Gates, Dorothy Olcott (Mrs. Frederick L.)
      Gehring, Edwin W.
      Gerould, Florence R.
      Getting, J. G. (Josette)
      Gifford, Annie K.
      Gilman, Charlotte Perkins
      Goding, Emily Tarbell
      Grace, Marion
      Graham, Amy
      Greene, Faith
      Greene, Francesca (see Morgan, Francesca)
      Greene, Harry Copley
      Greene, Rosalind (Mrs. H. Copley Greene)
      Greenough, Frances B.
      Greenough, Richard
      Gregg, Allen
      Grenfell, Wilfred T.
      Gretton, Mary S.
      Guild, Eleanor
      Guild, Harriet
      Guild, Marion P.
      Gulliver, Lucile
      Hale, Emily
      Hale, Mary
      Hale, Richard W.
      Hall, F. Josephine
      Hall, Minna B.
      Hall, Ownier
      Hall, Prescott F.
      Halladay, H. G.
      Hallowells
      Hamlen, E. P.
      Har, K. D. (Korea)
      Harper, Grace
      Harrington, Ruth
      Harrower
      Hart, Marion
      Haskell, Marion Alexander
      Haskell, Mary E.
      Haskell, Suzanne C.
      Hatch, Eugenie
      Hawkridge, Linda W.
      Hawley, Lillian S.
      Hatheway, Grace H.
      Healy, William (Dr.)
      Heard, Alice
      Henderson, George Dallas
      Henderson, Walter P. (Est.: Cohasset House)
      Higginson, T. W.
      Hildreth, John L.
      Hill, Edward B.
      Hill, Frederick Trevor
      Hocking, Richard
      Hocking, W. Ernest Agnes
      Hodder, Jessie
      Hogan, Lucy H.
      Holmes, Oliver Wendell
      Holt, Florence T.
      Homans, Caroline
      Homans, Helen A.
      Honey, James A.
      Hood, W. H. (Dr.)
      Hooper, Grace S.
      Hooper, J. Harry
      Hopkinson, Elinor
      Horne, H. H.
      Howe, Fanny R.
      Howe, Leonore
      Hull, Ida L.
      Hunt, Elizabeth (Mrs. Seth Hunt)
      Hunt, Hattie E.
      Huntington, Ellen B.
      Huntington, John P.
      Hutchins, Edward W. (Mrs. Susan B.)
      Jackson, Marion C.
      James, William
      Janeway, Eleanes C.
      Jeffries, Walter (re: a cotillion)
      Jennison, Katharine A.
      Johansen, Jean MacLane
      Johnson, Alma Strong
      Jones, Margaret
      Jordan, J. K.
      Kagan, B. I.
      Kapiud, Gretchen
      Kehew, Mary M.
      Keller, Helen
      Kellogg, Paul U.
      Kelly, Jane Sullivan (Mrs. Robert Palmer Kelly)
      Kern, Penelope V.
      Kimball, Anna
      Kimball, Stockton
      Kjellesirg, Morca Sophie (Mrs. K. E. Wiberg)
      Lamb, Edith M.
      Lambros, Mrs. S. C. G.
      Lausberg, Dorothy (see Lovitch, Dorothy Best)
      Lawson, Stuart J. (Dr.) Mary Lawson (Dr.)
      Leatherbee, Harriet
      Lee, Joseph Margaret
      Lee, Roger
      Lewis, Lena (Mrs. F. B. Lewis)
      Lloyd, J. J., Jr. (Dr.)
      Leigh, Francis B.
      Leighton, Ruth
      Lemon, Frances B.
      Littlefield, Maidie (Mrs. I. Littlefield)
      Locke?
      Loring, Mary G.
      Lothrop, Adele
      Lothrop, Amy
      Lothrop, Mary S. (poem)
      Lovell, Mrs. Walter
      Lovitch, Dorothy Best
      Lowell, Anna
      Lowell, Augustus
      Lowell, Lotta
      Lukens, Gertrude
      de Luze, Germaine
      Lyell, Katharine M.
      Lyman, Anne
      Lyman, Arthur T., Jr.
      Lyman, Charlotte
      Lyman, Elizabeth Gray
      Lyman, George T.
      Lyman, Mr. Mrs. Herbert (Ruth Whitney Lyman)
      Lyman, Julia (ELC sister)
      Lyman, Lydia W.
      Lyman, Mabel (ELC sister)
      Lyman, Margaret
      Lyman, Ronald T.
      Lyman, Susan (Mrs. Arthur T. Lyman, Jr.)
      Lyman, Theodore
      Mabie, H. W. (The Outlook)
      McClelland, George William
      McCormack, Ada (Friend of Cabots)
      McDowell, Maud A.
      McKenzie, Mary
      Mackintosh, James M.
      MacMillan, Pearl C.
      McSkimmon, Mary
      Maguire, Mary Hume
      Mahoney, John P. S., Sr. (and family - see also: Bradley, Margaret)
      Mallet, Laure
      de Maltchycé, M.
      Marcoe, Mrs. John
      "Maria" (Sister Maria)
      Marsh, Walter R.
      Marshall, Florence M.
      Marshall, George M.
      Martin, George H.
      Mason, Fanny P.
      Matteson, Helen Barber (Mrs. Paul Matteson)
      Mead, Frances S.
      Medan, Ida
      Medbery, Henry E.
      Meen, Edwin T.
      Merriman, Daniel
      Meyer, Nancy
      Miller, Dickinson S. (Dr.)
      Minis, Mary Haskell (letters to her from RCC - see also: Haskell, Mary E.)
      Minor, Charles L.
      Minot, Laurence
      Mitchell, Mary A.
      Mitchell, S. Weir (Dr.)
      Montague, Margaret Prescott
      Montessori, Maria
      Moors, Francis J. Marjory
      Moors, Mr. Mrs. John F. (Ethel Paine Moors)
      Moraes, Carlos Bello
      Morgan, Francesca Greene
      Morgan, Ruth
      Morison, Isabel
      Morse, Ethel
      Morse, Frances, R.
      Motley, Jane L. ("Jeannie")
      Moyer, A. Viola
      Munroe, Jessie R.
      Munsterberg, Hugo
      Murphy, Geraldine L.
      Nabers, Frank E. (Dr.)
      Nichols, Robert H. (Dr.)
      Nilez, Alfred S.
      Nolen, William W.
      Norwood, E. W. (Dr.)
      Norris, Cherry
      O'Brien, William
      O'Gorman, Alice
      Oliver, Madge (Military hospitals - France)
      Ordway, Julia K.
      O'Reilly, Bessy B.
      O'Reilly, Mary B.
      Osgood, Hamilton
      Osgood, Robert B. (Dr.)
      Osler, William (Sir) (Dr.)
      Page, Lilias
      Paine, Fanny
      Paine, George L.
      Paine, Lydia L.
      Paine, Robert Trent Elizabeth
      Painter, Florence
      Palmer, G. H.
      Paradise, F. I. (Rev.)
      Parker, A. (?)
      Parker, Truman A.
      Parkhurst, Fanny G.
      Parkman, Frances
      Parmenter, Esther
      Parson, Margaret (Mrs. Kenneth B. G. Parson)
      Parsons, Sara E.
      Passmore, Charlotte W.
      Passmore, Sarah M.
      Peabody, Francis G.
      Pear, William H.
      Pelton, Garnet
      Pendleton, E. Helen
      Pepper, Alice L.
      Perkins, Edith B.
      Perkins, Katrine
      Perkins, L. S. W.
      Perkins, Palfrey
      Perkins, Sarah S.
      Pernession, Noemi
      Philbrook, Ralph A.
      Phillips, John S.
      Pierrard, Luise P.
      Pigors, Faith Cabot
      Pigors, Paul J. W.
      Porter, Bruce
      Pottle, Juliet Wilbur Tompkins
      Pratt, Mary
      Preston, Augusta K. (Mrs.)
      Putnam, C. R. L.
      Putnam, E. C.
      Putnam, James P.
      Rathbone, Annie S.
      Reynolds, Harriet P.
      Reynolds, Mary R.
      Richardson, Louisa A.
      Richie, Edith K.
      Richmond, Rosita
      Rieker, Winifred
      Rigg, E. Harrison
      Ritter, R. H. (Dr.)
      Robbins, Laura R.
      Robbins, Reginald
      Roberts, Virginia Rhinelander
      Robins, Edward Blake
      Robins, Margaret Dreier
      Robinson, Annie Roosevelt
      Rochester, DeLancey
      Rodman, Warren A.
      Rogolsky, Freda
      Ross, G. A. Johnston
      Rousmaniere, Frances
      Royce, Josiah
      Royce, Ruth
      Russell, Bess Lynde
      Russell, Ellen F.
      Russell, Helena M.
      Samoylenko, Elizabeth (Dr.)
      Samper (de) Doris (see Baldwin family)
      Sampsen, Lilian V.
      Sampson, Edith F.
      Sands, William J.
      Sandwith, F.
      Sanford, Erskine
      Santayana, George (Prof.)
      Saye, Caroline ( Sele)
      Schlesinger, Mary
      Schneider, A.
      Scott, J. W. L.
      Schweigert, Mrs. Edward A. (Ode)
      Scull, Marie
      Sears, Annie Lyman
      Sears, Lerlyn
      Sears, Mary P.
      Seaver, Nathanael (Rev.)
      Sedgewick, S.
      Selhr (von), Margaret
      Selincourt (de), Basil
      Sergeant, Elizabeth S.
      Sessions, Mrs. T. F. (Ella)
      Sharp, Waitstill Hastings
      Shattuck, F. C. (Dr. Frederick C.)
      Shaw
      Shepard, Margaret J.
      Short, Josephine H.
      Sills, Ethel Payne
      Simonds, Julia Lyman
      Sisson, John
      Slater, Eleanor
      Small, Alice H.
      Smillie, Wilson G.
      Smith, Alice Weston
      Smith, Edith Livingston
      Smith, Joseph Lindon
      Smoot, Sadie
      Smyth, Anna Lee
      Sohier, William D.
      Sorokin, P.
      Soulsby, Lucy H.
      Speight, Harold E. B.
      Sprague, Mrs. Frank B. ("Lissie")
      Spring, Romney
      Stalker, Hugh Lyle
      Stannard, Margaret
      Starkweather, Esther
      Steel, William (Dr.)
      Sternlib, Louis
      Stevens, Emily
      Stevens, Hattie Brooks
      Stewart, Florence H.
      Stiles, Ch. Wardell
      Stocktons (Dr. Charles daughter, Lucy)
      Storer, Edith
      Storrow, James J.
      Straate, (van) T.
      Sullivan-Kelly, Jane Valentine
      Tack, Violet
      Taylor, Katharine
      Thayer, Alfred H.
      Thayer, W. S. (Col.)
      Thomas, Florence
      Thomas, Hal
      Thomas, Zoe
      Thompson, Geraldine (Mrs. Lewis S. Thompson)
      Thoron, Ward
      Thurston, Edmund H.
      Tileston, Mary W. (Mrs. John B.)
      Timmins, Sara G.
      Tompkins, Juliet Wilbur (see Pottle, Juliet Wilbur Tompkins)
      Tufts, Susan C.
      Vernes, Arthur (Dr.)
      Vieillot, Marie Thérèse
      Vomsfield, C. E.
      Walker, Sylvia Cabot ("Bunny")
      Warren, Charles
      Warren, Gretchen (Mrs. Fisk Warren)
      Washburn, Edith H.
      Watahiki, T.
      Watson, John H.
      Waugh, W. F. (Dr.)
      Welch, William H.
      Weld, George
      Wells, Fannie
      Wells, Kate Gannet
      Wells, Louise
      Wesselhoft, Emily B.
      Wheeler, Agnes G.
      Wheeler, Hetty Shepard
      Wheelwright, Andrew C.
      Wheelwright, S. G.
      White, Edith Hamilton
      White, Evan
      Whiting, Dorothea
      Whiting, Margaret L. G.
      Whiteley, Opal
      Whitman, Sarah (Mrs. Henry Whitman)
      Whitner Dorothy
      Whitney, Mrs. Casper
      Whitney, Emily
      Wilbur, R. H.
      Williams, Linsly R. (Dr.)
      Wilson, Louis B. (Dr.)
      Wilson, Sally
      Winslow, Mrs. Frederick
      Wiswall, Harriet
      Wolbach, Burt Anna
      Wolcott, Edith Prescott
      Wolcott, H. P.
      Wood, T. Kenneth
      Worcester, E.
      Worcester, Joseph
      Wright, Lucy
      Letters fragments of letters (mostly unidentified)
      Letters from doctors re: "Medical Expert Testimony."
    - Additional Correspondence, 1907-1939, (2 boxes); HUG 4255.11
      Consists primarily of original correspondence of Richard Clarke Cabot and Ella Lyman Cabot with Alice O'Gorman.
      - Canon, Ida M., Copies of letters from RCC to, 1907-1936 (Box Box 1)
      - Guiles, Austin Philip, 1929-39 (copies) (Box Box 1)
      - Gluecks, Mrs. Sheldon, 1932-39 (copies) (Box Box 1)
      - Medical Social Science, Notes by RCC re. (Box Box 1)
      - Sarton, George, 1935-1939 (copies) (Box Box 1)
      - Sarton, May, 1935-1939 (copies) (Box Box 1)
      - Letters: RCC and ELC to Alice O'Gorman, 1911-1915 and 1917-1927, (10 folders) (Box Box 1)
      - Letters: RCC and ELC to Alice O'Gorman, 1928-1939, (8 folders) (Box Box 2)
    - Letters between Richard Clarke Cabot and Ella Lyman Cabot exchanged during World War I, 1917-1919., (3 boxes); HUG 4255.15
      - Letter case, used for France (?) WWI (Box Box 1)
      - Index to War Letters (Box Box 1)
      - ELC War Letters, excerpts, May 1917-January 1919, (10 folders) (Box Box 1)
      - ELC War Letters, excerpts, January-March 1918 (Box Box 2:)
      - RCC War Letters, excerpts, July 1917-January 1919, (8 folders) (Box Box 2)
      - War Letters, RCC to ELC, September 1917-August 1918, (10 folders) (Box Box 3)
    - Correspondence with Dr. Harry Linenthal, 1913, (photocopies); HUG 4255.20
      Accession number 9382; received from Arthur Linenthal.
      Concerns Dr. Linenthal's appointment to staff of Massachusetts General Hospital.
    - Correspondence, 1920-1930's, (1 box); HUG 4255.21
      Accession number: 7682; received from Schlesinger Library; material came from the Greene Family Collection.
      Contains miscellaneous correspondence from 1920-1930s A
      - Letters of recommendation by RCC, 1924-1938
      - Misc. Correspondence, 1920s-1930s, (2 folders)
      - Misc. Writings, prefaces, etc.
      - Simmons College
      - Resignation from Harvard
      - Testimony in court case: Dondore vs. Rohner, Iowa, 1935
  - Writings
    - Reprints of articles by R. C. Cabot, 1894-1929., (3 boxes); HUG 4255.25
      - Reprints, 1894-1913 (Box Box 1)
      - Reprints, 1899-1929 (Box Box 3)
      - Reprints (Box Box 2)
      - Uses and Abuses of Psychotherapy (Box Box 2)
      - Psychotherapy, 1908-1909 (Box Box 2)
    - Books
      - Richard C. Cabot. The Meaning of Right and Wrong, (typescript; 1 box); HUG 4255.27
      - Richard C. Cabot. A Layman's Handbook of Medicine, rev. ed. Houghton Mifflin Co., 1936., (1 volume); HUG 4255.75
      - Richard C. Cabot and Russell L. Dicks, The Art of Ministering to the Sick New York: MacMillian, 1959., (1 volume); HUG 4255.76
      - E. Milton Grant Coming of age: a frank study of the problems of adolescence. Fleming Revell Co., 1939., (1 volume); HUG 4255.81
        Introduction by Richard C. Cabot
      - Sarah Whitman. Merrymount Press, 1944, (1 volume); HUG 4255.82
        A record of her memorial service; address by Richard C. Cabot, p. 9
    - Creation Papers: The Creative Power of God, (4 boxes); HUG 4255.28
      Contains Richard Clarke Cabot's research material for and manuscript of the Creative Power of God.
      Also includes lecture notes and papers relating to a course Cabot gave at Andover-Newton Theological Seminary in 1938-1939.
      - Creative Power of God, misc. (Box Box 1)
      - Testimony of Creative Artists (Box Box 1)
      - Creation and the Middle Voice (Box Box 1)
      - What is the Soul? (R.H.) (Box Box 1)
      - Death in Life (R.H.) (Box Box 1)
      - Necessity, Obedience, Courage (Box Box 1)
      - Education (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty: Symb. of RWE, Shelley, Caritt, Aug. 1938 (Box Box 1)
      - Contrast of Prose Poetry IV 16/ Ugliness IV 14 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty as release III 9 (Box Box 1)
      - Delight III 2 × 15 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty in what arouses... II 30 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty as transforming (Box Box 1)
      - The Poet as the creative man II 28 (Box Box 1)
      - What streams with Life II 23, 26 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty as a chain of remembrance II 20 (Box Box 1)
      - Imagination I 18 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty Creator of the Cosmos I 17 21 (Box Box 1)
      - Symbols I 7 (Box Box 1)
      - Expression Creates (Box Box 1)
      - Expression I 5 (Box Box 1)
      - Harmony I 4 (Box Box 1)
      - Beauty=Imitation (of something) so truth possessing I 3 (Box Box 1)
      - Heightened Perception (Box Box 1)
      - The Beatific Vision Charts (Illustrations) (Box Box 1)
      - Schedules Summaries (Box Box 1)
      - Current Schedules of Classes, Radcliffe, Andover-Newton, Boston, and Simmons (Box Box 1)
      - Fragments for the Book - Single-Page Fragments (Box Box 1)
      - Fragments for the Book including... Education (Box Box 1)
      - Fragments for the Book... Creation (Box Box 1)
      - Creation - Carbon copies of typed parts (Box Box 1)
      - Creation - Carbon copies of typed parts - Short Fragments March 1939 (Box Box 1)
      - Creation - Original Ms. which has been copied before May 7, 1939 (Box Box 1)
      - N.S.L. Unfiled Material (Box Box 1)
      - Lecture Outline (Box Box 2)
      - The sort of thing we mean by Creation (early in book if at all) (Box Box 2)
      - The Ideal - basic root of creativeness (Box Box 2)
      - 2 comments on Evolution History (Box Box 2)
      - Creation the basic certainties presupposed in it (Box Box 2)
      - Table of Contents (Box Box 2)
      - Beauty in Creation (Box Box 2)
      - Lectures 1-37 and 40-49 (Box Box 2)
      - Reading Notes, 1938 (Box Box 3)
      - Reading Notes (Box Box 3)
      - Need Growth (Box Box 3)
      - References on Creation (Box Box 3)
      - Creation (Box Box 3)
      - "Creative Mind" Spearman reading notes (Box Box 3)
      - Bergon "Creative Evolution" (Reading Notes) (Box Box 3)
      - Evolution 3, 4, 5 (Box Box 3)
      - Vis Medicatrix Dei (Box Box 3)
      - Vis Nutrix (Growth Prayer) (Box Box 3)
      - In the Soul of Man (Box Box 3)
      - Invisible Leadership (Box Box 3)
      - Lecture 18-19 Emerson's Self Reliance, Nov. 20 30, 1928 (Box Box 3)
      - "The Growing Edge" (secondary material) (Box Box 3)
      - The Urge and the Sense of Growth (Box Box 3)
      - How to help another's growth (Box Box 3)
      - Stimulants in Growth (Box Box 3)
      - Giving and receiving (in Growth) (Box Box 3)
      - Misc. (Box Box 3)
      - The role of consciousness in spiritual growth (Box Box 3)
      - Beauty in Creation (Box Box 3)
      - Beauty and Spontaneity in Creation (Box Box 3)
      - Paradox, signal of Creation near (Box Box 3)
      - Invention: Creative scientific work, John Tyndall (Box Box 3)
      - Intuition Creation (Box Box 3)
      - Faith, Love, Creation (Box Box 3)
      - Creation Providence (Box Box 3)
      - Evil as overrunning (Box Box 3)
      - Growth the Eternal (Box Box 3)
      - Perishing Creation (Box Box 3)
      - The Creative Power of God. Notes for Lectures in Theology 8, Andover-Newton Theological School, 1934 (Box Box 4)
      - The Creative Power of God, 2nd Term,1938 (Box Box 4)
      - Student Quizzes (Box Box 4)
      - Lectures, The Creative Power of God, 1938, (4 folders) (Box Box 4)
  - Teaching material, (3 boxes); HUG 4255.40
    Contains outlines of courses and student work from courses in social ethics and sociology; also contains a large scrapbook for sociology
    - Social Ethics A, 1920-1932, (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
      RESTRICTION PENDING.
    - Stencils used in Social Ethics A (Box Box 1)